import { Quiz, QuizQuestion } from '../../types';

const PrepositionsQuiz: Quiz[] = [
  {
    description: 'Opakujte v angličtině',
    name: 'Předložky',
    questions: [
      {
        answer: ['opposite'],
        question: 'naproti'
      },
      {
        answer: ['left'],
        question: 'vlevo'
      },
      {
        answer: ['to the left'],
        question: 'doleva'
      },
      {
        answer: ['straight ahead', 'straight', 'straight on'],
        question: 'rovně'
      },
      {
        answer: ['right'],
        question: 'vpravo'
      },
      {
        answer: ['to the right'],
        question: 'doprava'
      },
      {
        answer: ['back', 'backwards'],
        question: 'zpět'
      },
      {
        answer: ['back', 'backwards'],
        question: 'zpátky'
      },
      {
        answer: ['beyond'],
        question: 'mimo'
      },
      {
        answer: ['around'],
        question: 'kolem'
      },
      {
        answer: ['after'],
        question: 'po'
      },
      {
        answer: ['on'],
        question: 'na'
      },
      {
        answer: ['beside', 'next to'],
        question: 'vedle'
      },
      {
        answer: ['above'],
        question: 'nad'
      },
      {
        answer: ['in'],
        question: 'v'
      },
      {
        answer: ['inside'],
        question: 'uvnitř'
      },
      {
        answer: ['between'],
        question: 'mezi'
      },
      {
        answer: ['in front of', 'in front', 'before'],
        question: 'před'
      },
      {
        answer: ['for'],
        question: 'pro'
      },
      {
        answer: ['behind'],
        question: 'za'
      },
      {
        answer: ['under', 'beneath'],
        question: 'pod'
      },
      {
        answer: ['against'],
        question: 'proti'
      },
      {
        answer: ['down'],
        question: 'dolů'
      },
      {
        answer: ['near'],
        question: 'blízko'
      },
      {
        answer: ['nearby'],
        question: 'poblíž'
      },
      {
        answer: ['about'],
        question: 'o'
      },
      {
        answer: ['across', 'via'],
        question: 'přes'
      },
      {
        answer: ['as'],
        question: 'jak'
      },
      {
        answer: ['according to', 'by'],
        question: 'podle'
      },
      {
        answer: ['until'],
        question: 'až'
      },
      {
        answer: ['despite', 'in spite of'],
        question: 'navzdory'
      },
      {
        answer: ['during'],
        question: 'během'
      },
      {
        answer: ['except'],
        question: 'vyjma'
      },
      {
        answer: ['toward', 'to'],
        question: 'k'
      },
      {
        answer: ['into'],
        question: 'do'
      }
    ]
  }
];

export default PrepositionsQuiz;
